I just want to mention one thing that's part of a routine that's a little bit more personal about our
我只想提一件事，它是我们日常生活的一部分
sleeping habits.
睡眠习惯。
So if we say that we get up or we wake up Are these the same.
因此，如果我们说我们起床或醒来，这些是否相同。
Not exactly no.
不完全没有。
So if you say that you get up that means you get out of bed and maybe you get dressed for the day you
所以如果你说你起床了，那意味着你起床了，也许你会穿好衣服
get dressed that means you put your clothes on you get dressed or you get ready get ready for the day.
穿好衣服，这意味着你穿上你的衣服，或者你准备好迎接这一天。
Right.
正确的。
But if you say you wake up that does not mean that you get up.
但如果你说你醒了，那并不意味着你就醒了。
Getting up is this action getting out of bed getting ready.
起床是起床准备的这个动作。
Waking up is just opening your eyes.
醒来只是睁开眼睛。
So some people say I usually wake up around eight thirty but I don't get up until 9:00.
所以有人说我通常在八点三十分左右起床，但我直到 9:00 才起床。
So maybe from eight thirty until 9:00 you're just I don't know checking your Instagram or whatever you're
所以也许从八点三十分到 9:00 你只是我不知道检查你的 Instagram 或者你是什么
doing right.
做对了。
You wake up.
你醒了。
That means you're not sleeping anymore and then you play around on your phone and then you get up and
这意味着你不再睡觉，然后你玩手机，然后你起床
get ready for the day.
为这一天做好准备。
So those are different sleeping in.
所以睡在里面是不一样的。
Does this mean that we go to sleep late or does it mean we sleep for a long time.
这是否意味着我们睡得晚了，还是意味着我们睡了很长时间。
OK.
好的。
So sleeping in means we get up very late.
所以睡觉意味着我们起得很晚。
Not go to bed late get up late so maybe you usually get up at eight o'clock seven o'clock.
不晚睡晚起所以也许你通常八点七点起床。
But today you slept in.
但是今天你睡了。
You decided to sleep in until 10 thirty a.m. ten thirty in the morning.
你决定睡到早上十点三十分。
Oh I really slept in today.
哦，我今天真的睡了。
I don't know why I was so sleepy.
我不知道我为什么这么困。
I slept in.
我睡了。
I got up late go to bed go to sleep.
我起晚了睡觉去睡觉。
Are these the same again.
这些又是一样的吗。
It's kind of like get up.
这有点像起床。
Wake up you could go to bed at 10:00 and then not go to sleep until 12:00 maybe for two hours you're
醒来你可以在 10:00 上床睡觉，然后直到 12:00 才睡觉，可能要等两个小时
playing with your phone again.
又玩手机了。
I don't know.
我不知道。
But you don't go to sleep until a certain time you don't close your eyes and maybe until 12:00.
但是直到某个时间你才开始睡觉，你没有闭上眼睛，也许直到 12:00。 因此，要明确上床睡觉并不意味着睡觉。
But people often say them as the same thing.
但是人们经常说它们是同一件事。
I'm gonna go to bed that suggests that you're going to go to sleep.
我要睡觉了，这表明你要睡觉了。
Right.
正确的。
But I just want to be clear that you can use them separately if you want to because they're not exactly
但我只是想明确一点，如果你愿意，你可以单独使用它们，因为它们并不完全
the same.
相同。